Shahid Ullah

+923339141083 shahid80qau@gmail.com Skype: shahidullah79

Profile

12+ year of experience in Software Development, Software Quality Assurance and software testing in the domain of web and desktop application.

Specialist skills includes Automation, Quality Control, Quality Assurance, Implementation and maintenance of Client applications.

In Automation I have practical proved experience in designing, implementation an automation framework and writing automation scripts using Python.

In QC I have practical proved experience in Functionality, regression, stress, performance, load testing.

In depth knowledge of testing methodologies, testing strategies, testing tools, test case development, test process management, and defect management.

Knowledge of BPM, Business Processes Engineering/Re engineering and Automation of Business processes in Ultimus.

I have good knowledge of different EnterpriseDB tools.

Knowledge and experience of configuration management, software engineering, specification methods, and development processes.

Testing Experience on Office Automation and Workflow based systems.

I have practical experience in Python 2.7, Python 3.5, Bash scripting, database administration and PostgreSQL.

Knowledge of C++, C#, VB.Net, Oracle, Developer, ASP.Net, SQL Server 2000

Experience

Principal QAE, EnterpriseDB; Islamabad, Pakistan - 2017-PRESENT

I am responsible to manage QMG automation department.

I have design and implement a specialized cross platform automation framework using Python. The framework is used for to automate EDB different modules installation, uninstallation, Package and functional verification.

SR. QAE, ENTERPRISEDB; ISLAMABAD, PAKISTAN - 2010-2017

I am responsible to manage and execute Testing activities on different DBMS tools.

Testing Experience on HPUX, Solaris Sparc, Solaris x86, Linux 32/64 (RHEL, OPENSUSE, SLES, Ubuntu, Fedora, CentOS) Windows 32/64 (All windows releases)

Perform RPM and Installer testing (Bitrock, Installed Shield)

Perform DBMS functional testing.

Task, Time & Risk management across the distributed teams.

Functionality, Compatibility, Reliability, Usability, installation, security and related test methodologies.

Automated testing on DB Server

QA Lead, VCSL: Islamabad, Pakistan - 2009-2010

I joined VCSL as Lead QA Engineer. I responsible to do analysis, design different modules test plan and test cases, coordination with development teams to implement these test plans for different module and perform testing.

Module owner of Cryo Stubbing Server, CryoStubbingClient, CryoCacheBuilder,Cryo Stubbing Transport Agent.

Main responsibilities:

Defining and implementing QA Smoke, Performance, Functional and Regression Test Processes. Preparation, communication, execution and monitoring of test plan. Reviewing and optimizing existing test cases and defining new test cases.

Resolution of technical issues with Development Team.

Analyzing test cases for automation.

Working on QTP for automation.

Using NUnit for API testing.

Update and maintain bugzilla

QAE, ULITIMS, ISLAMABAD, PAKISTAN - 2006-2009

Worked on Ultimus BPM Suite V8.0 SP 1 and V8.1.

Module Owner of Rich client(desktop) and thin client(Web) of Ultimus BPM Suite (Business Process Management).

Perform Functionality, Performance, Stress, Load, Usability, Security, Regression testing on Multiple Microsoft Platforms

Implement HCI Model.

Perform Automation testing.

Improve QA processes with the coordination of manager/TL.

As for as QA is concerned I was Member SEPG (worked on Change Management Process, Enhancement Process and FSD (Function Specification Document) Template Finalization etc).

Education

Quaid-e-Azam University Islamabad, Pakistan - M.Sc. Computer Science 2001-2002

Skills

Python 2.7, Python 3.5, Bash scripting, database administration and PostgreSQL. Knowledge of C++, C#, VB.Net, Oracle, Developer, ASP.Net, SQL Server 2000 Working experience of HPUX, Solaris Sparc, Solaris x86, Linux 32/64 (RHEL, OPENSUSE, SLES, Ubuntu, Fedora, CentOS) Windows 32/64 (All windows releases)

Training:

Scrum & Jira Quick Start Training
Introduction to PostgreSQL Administration
Advance PostgreSQL Administration
Introduction to Postgres Plus Cloud Database PostgreSQL 9.2 Techniques for Backup and Recovery Introduction to PEM
Introduction to xDB Replication

Certification:

EDB Certified Associate - Postgres Advanced Server 9.6 - Date: Jun 2017

EDB Certified Professional - Postgres Advanced Server 9.4 - Date: Sep 2015

EDB Certified Associate - Postgres Advanced Server 9.4 - Date: May 2015